Donald Barthelme, Sr. Architectural Papers, 1924-1997
University of Houston Libraries
- Photographic Materials
  Barthelme’s photographic materials consist of black-and-white prints in various sizes, including 8 x 10, 11 x 14, and 16 x 20; and black-and-white negatives in 4 x 5, 2 ¼ x 3 ¼, and 35 mm. Most of the color images are 2 ¼ x 3 ¼ glass-mount transparencies and 35mm color slides. Many of the pictures of Barthelme’s projects are known to be the work of Dallas photographer Ulric Meisel, but unless indicated otherwise, Barthelme is presumed to be the photographer on all of the items in this series.
  In the category of “photographic prints” is a scrapbook of prints and clippings about Barthelme’s projects that he kept during his career. Many of the prints have separated from the leaves of the scrapbook, and because he later removed the spiral binding, the order of the items is approximate. Important awards, certificates, and licenses that had become loose were removed to a separate folder for such items, but duplicates or those that were securely mounted remain in the scrapbook. These include the A.I.A. Award of Merit for St. Rose of Lima Church (1949); the “Texas Architecture 1952” exhibition Award of Merit for Sweeny Elementary School; The School Executive Competition for Better School Design, Special Feature Award for Sweeny Elementary (1952); and the Houston Chapter A.I.A. Award of Merit for Sweeny H.S. additions (undated). The scrapbook comprises 120 prints (mounted and unmounted) and 72 leaves, or 116 total items.
  - Prints: 8 x 10 (Box 21)
    - Portrait, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Portraits (8 x 10), 1940s-1960s (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Portraits (5 x 7), 1950s, 1970s (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Portraits (small), Series A, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Portraits (small), Series B, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Portraits (small), Series C, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Portraits DB, Charles and Arthur Flynn, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Portraits Donald Barthelme, Jr., 1950's (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Conference, 1950's (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - TSA Convention, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Education Conference, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - APC Building Presentation, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Early Projects, Galveston, 1933-1934 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Contemporary House, Centennial Exposition, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Beers Kenison Office, Galveston, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Karl Milles Sculpture, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified Apartments, 1950's (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Dargan Doctor’s Office, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Barthelme House (exteriors), 1945-1955 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Barthelme House (interiors), 1952 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - St. Rose of Lima Church, Pts. 1-11, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 21-31)
    - St. Rose of Lima Church, Models and Construction, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - St. Rose of Lima School Additions, Pts. 1-2, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 33-34)
    - Competitions (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Growit Yourself College (Rice Charrette), 1962 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Snake, undated (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Sweeny High School Additions, Pts. 1-5, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 1-5)
    - Sweeny High School Gymnasium, Pts. 1-2, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
    - Sweeny High School Auditorium, Pts. 1-3, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 8-10)
    - Sweeny Negro (Carver) School, Pts. 1-4, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 11-14)
    - Sweeny Elementary School, Pts. 1-16, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 1-16)
    - Highland Heights Elementary, Pts. 1-3, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 17-19)
    - West Columbia School Auditorium, Pts. 1-2, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
    - West Columbia Elementary School, Pts. 1-12, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 3-14)
    - West Columbia High School Band Building, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - West Columbia High School Home Mgt. Building, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Adams Petroleum Center, Pts. 1-9, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 1-9)
  - Prints: 11 x 14 (Box 26)
    - Portraits, 1950's (Box 26)
    - St. Rose of Lima Church and School, 1948 (Box 26)
    - First Christian Church, 1955 (Box 26)
    - Adams Petroleum Center, 1958 (Box 26)
    - Sweeny High School Additions, 1948 (Box 26)
    - West Columbia Elementary School, 1952 (Box 27)
    - West Columbia Senior High School, 1963 (Box 27)
    - West Columbia School Auditorium, 1948 (Box 27)
    - Stadium scene, Mexico, 1951 (Box 27)
    - Growit Yourself College (Rice Charrette), 1962 (Box 27)
    - Michigan Conference (Trump Report), 1959 (Box 27)
    - Sweeny Elementary School, 1952 (Box 27)
    - Sweeny Negro (Carver) School, 1952 (Box 27)
    - Negro (Charlie Brown) School Gymnasium, 1951 (Box 27)
    - West Columbia High School (old), 1951 (Box 27)
    - Highland Heights Elementary School, 1959 (Box 27)
    - Mexico (Taxco), 1950's (Box 28)
    - Mexico (Taxco), 1950's (Box 29)
  - Prints: 16 x 20 (mounted) (Box 30)
    - Barthelme House (interiors), 1952 (Box 30)
    - St. Rose of Lima Church and School, 1948 (Box 30)
    - West Columbia Elementary School, 1952 (Box 30)
    - Sweeny Elementary School, 1952 (Box 30)
    - Highland Heights Elementary School, 1959 (Box 30)
    - Adams Petroleum Center, 1958 (Box 30)
    - First Christian Church, 1955 (Box 30)
    - Michigan Conference (Trump Report), 1959 (Box 30)
  - Prints: 16 x 20 (unmounted) (Box 31)
    - St. Rose of Lima Church and School, 1948 (Box 31)
    - West Columbia Elementary School, 1952 (Box 31)
    - Sweeny Elementary School, 1952 (Box 31)
    - West Columbia School Auditorium, 1948 (Box 31)
    - Sweeny High School Additions, 1948 (Box 31)
    - Adams Petroleum Center, 1958 (Box 31)
    - Mexico, 1950's (Box 31)
  - Scrapbook (Box 32)
    - Scrapbook, undated (Box 32)
  - Negatives: 4 x 5 (Box 33)
    - St. Rose of Lima Church and School, 1947-1953 (Box 33)
    - Barthelme House, 1950-1953 (Box 33)
    - First Christian Church, 1953 (Box 33)
    - Adams Petroleum Center, 1954, 1958 (Box 33)
    - Highland Heights Elementary School, 1960 (Box 33)
    - Kellaway House, 1964 (Box 33)
    - Sweeny Elementary School, 1950-1953 (Box 34)
    - Sweeny Negro (Carver) School, 1951-1952, 1959 (Box 34)
    - Sweeny High School Additions, 1951-1952 (Box 34)
    - West Columbia School Auditorium, 1946 (Box 35)
    - West Columbia Elementary School, 1950-1952 (Box 35)
    - Negro (Charlie Brown) School, 1951-1954 (Box 35)
    - West Columbia Senior High School, 1963 (Box 35)
    - Barthelme Portraits, 1954-1966 (Box 36)
    - Classes-University of Houston, Rice, 1953-1966 (Box 36)
    - Hotel Site-Prospective, 1954 (Box 36)
    - Carson Pirie Scott Competition, 1954 (Box 36)
    - Michigan Conference-Trump Report, 1959 (Box 36)
    - A.I.A. Headquarters Competition, 1964 (Box 36)
    - San Francisco Competition, 1965 (Box 36)
    - Yale Competition, 1970 (Box 36)
    - Art Center Competition, undated (Box 36)
  - Negatives: 2 ¼ x 3 ¼ (Box 37)
    - West Columbia Auditorium, 1947-1949 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Barthelme House, 1947-1952 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - St. Rose of Lima Church and School, 1947-1949 (Box 37, Folder 3-5)
    - Sweeny High School, Pts. 1-2, 1948-1952 (Box 37, Folder 6-7)
    - Sweeny Elementary, Pts. 1-2, 1950-1952 (Box 37, Folder 8-9)
    - Negro (Charlie Brown) School, 1950-1951 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - West Columbia Elementary, Pts. 1-4, 1950-1952 (Box 37, Folder 11-14)
    - Sweeny Negro (Carver) School, 1951-1952 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous: projects, competitions, faculty meetings, 1946-1952 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Negatives: 35mm (Box 37)
    - Sweeny High School Addition, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - St. Rose of Lima Church and School, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Dargan Doctors Office, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Barthelme House in the Snow, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - West Columbia Elementary, 1951 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Carver Elementary Additions, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Highland Heights Elementary, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - APC Building, c. 1960 (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - Rice Charrette, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - Competition boards, c. 1960s (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Transparencies: 4 x 5 Glass Mount (Box 38)
    - West Columbia Elementary School, 1952 (Box 38)
    - St. Rose of Lima Church and School, 1948 (Box 39)
    - Sweeny High School Additions, 1948 (Box 39)
    - Sweeny Negro (Carver) School, 1952 (Box 39)
    - Sweeny Elementary School, 1952 (Box 39)
  - Transparencies: 35mm slides, Projects (Box 40)
    - St. Rose of Lima Church and School, 1948-1953 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Sweeny High School Addition, 1948-1952 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Sweeny Elementary School, 1950-1953 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Sweeny Negro (Carver) School, 1951-1952 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Carver Elementary (Sweeny Negro) School, 1955, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - West Columbia High School Auditorium, 1948-1949 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - West Columbia Elementary School, 1951-1952 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - West Columbia Junior High School, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - West Columbia Senior High School, 1960, 1963 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Highland Heights Elementary School, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - First Christian, apartments, materials, 1955 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Adams Petroleum Center, 1956-1957 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Rice Charrette, UH architecture studio, 1962, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Michigan Conference (Trump Report), 1959 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Transparencies: 35mm slides, Travel (Box 42)
    - Cranbrook, 1951 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - St. Louis, New Orleans, San Francisco, Chicago, 1950 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - New York, 1960, 1964 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Cornell, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Harvard, Yale, 1964 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Washington, D.C., 1964 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Nature, 1949-1953 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Mexico trip with Mamie[Barthelme’s mother], ca. 1960 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Mexican modern architecture, 1958-1964 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Mexico City, Taxco, 1951, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Mexico City, Taxco, 1951, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Bacardi Factory (Felix Candela), 1960 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Taxco, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Taxco, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Mexico City, Xochimilco, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Mexico City, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Churches (Felix Candela), undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Puerto Vallarta, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Mexico, bullfight, undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Taxco, 1954, 1955 (Box 43, Folder 12)
- Digital Images (Family)
  This series consists of digital files of part of Barthelme’s collection of family photographs, which were retained by the heirs. Approximately 150 sheets of negatives are preserved in 2887 digital images on CD-ROM, with record prints in a binder. This is intended only as a study collection for scholars. The images are owned by the Barthelme estate and may not be copied or reproduced without its written permission. Barthelme’s original binder and negative sheet numbers are noted.
  - CD-ROMs (Box 44)
  - CD-ROMs (Box 45)
  - Section 2 (Cd-rom BAR001, File Barthelme Binder 1)
    - bar001 – bar002 1932, Philadelphia
    - bar003 – bar005 pre-1932, Philadelphia
    - bar006 1932-1933, Galveston
  - (Cd-rom BAR002, File Barthelme Binder 1)
    - bar007 1932-1933, Galveston
    - bar008 – bar009 1935-1936
    - bar010 1939
    - Section 3
    - bar011 – bar012 1941-1942
    - bar013 1939
  - (Cd-rom BAR003, File Barthelme Binder 1)
    - bar014 – bar015 1947
    - bar016 1947 House
    - Section 4
    - bar017 – bar021 1948
  - (Cd-rom BAR004, File Barthelme Binder 1)
    - bar022 1948
    - Section 5
    - bar023 – bar029 1949
  - (Cd-rom BAR005, File Barthelme Binder 1)
    - bar030 1949
    - Section 1 (File Barthelme Binder 2)
    - bar031 – bar034 1950 Family (sheets B-2, B-12, B-13, B-15)
    - bar035 – bar036 1950 Donald Jr. (sheets B-19)
  - (Cd-rom BAR006, File Barthelme Binder 2)
    - bar037 – bar040 1950 Donald Jr. (sheets B-20, B-21)
    - bar041 1950 Family Color (sheet B-22)
    - bar042 – bar043 1950 Family (sheets B-22, B-24)
  - (Cd-rom BAR007, File Barthelme Binder 2)
    - bar044 – bar045 1950 Donald Sr. (sheet B-25)
    - bar046 1950 Family at table (sheet B-26)
    - bar047 1950 Family, Donald Sr. office (sheet B-30)
    - Section 2
    - bar048 1951 Family, House (sheet B-39)
    - bar049 1951 Family, Donald Sr. office (sheet B-40)
    - bar050 1951 Family, Faculty (sheet B-41)
  - (Cd-rom BAR008, File Barthelme Binder 2)
    - bar051 1951 Family
    - bar052 – bar054 1951 Family–color (sheet B-46)
    - bar055 – bar056 1951 Donald Jr. (sheet B-47)
  - (Cd-rom BAR009, File Barthelme Binder 2)
    - bar057 – bar060 1951 Family (sheet B-49)
    - bar061 1951 Donald Jr. (sheet B-51)
    - bar062 1951 Family (sheet B-54)
    - bar063 1951 Donald Sr. (sheet B-62)
    - bar064 1951 Family (sheet B-70)
  - (Cd-rom BAR010, File Barthelme Binder 2)
    - Section 3
    - bar065 – bar066 1952 Donald Jr. and Marilyn (sheet B-81)
    - bar067 1952 (sheet B-82)
    - bar068 1952 Family–color (sheet B-85)
    - bar069 1952 Family (sheet B-85)
    - bar070 1952 Family (sheet B-87)
  - (Cd-rom BAR011, File Barthelme Binder 2)
    - bar071 1952 Family, Christmas (sheet B-88)
    - bar072 1952 Family, Christmas (sheet B-90)
    - bar073 1952 Donald Jr. wedding (sheet B-95)
    - bar074 1952 House remodeling (sheet B-96) (File Barthelme Binder 3)
    - Section 1
    - bar075 1953 Family (2nd unnumbered sheet)
    - bar076 – bar077 1953 Donald Jr., Marilyn–color (10th sheet)
  - (Cd-rom BAR012, File Barthelme Binder 3)
    - bar078 1953 Donald Jr., Marilyn (10th sheet)
    - bar079 1953 Helen and children (11th sheet)
    - bar080 1953 Helen and children–color (12th sheet)
    - bar081 1953 Helen and children (12th sheet)
    - bar082 1953 Donald Sr., Helen (13th sheet)
  - (Cd-rom BAR013, File Barthelme Binder 3)
    - bar083 1953 Donald Sr., Helen (14th sheet)
    - bar084 1953 Family Portrait (17th sheet)
    - bar085 1953 Family (21st sheet)
    - bar086 1953 Family (29th sheet)
    - bar087 1953 Marilyn (48th sheet)
    - bar088 1953 Marilyn (49th sheet)
    - Section 2
    - bar089 1954 Donald Sr. office (51st sheet)
    - bar090 1954 Donald Sr. and Helen (64th sheet)
    - bar091 1954 Donald Sr. (67th sheet)
  - (Cd-rom BAR014, File Barthelme Binder 3)
    - bar092 1955 Donald Sr. (69th sheet)
    - bar093 1955 Family (70th sheet)
    - bar094 1956 Donald Sr. (77th sheet)
    - bar095 1956 1956 Family (78th sheet)
    - bar096 – bar098 1958 Christmas, Corvette–color (94th sheet)
    - bar099 1958 Donald Sr. (99th sheet)
  - (Cd-rom BAR015, File Barthelme Binder 4)
    - Section 1
    - bar100 1959 Donald Sr. (sheet D-1)
    - bar101 1959 Donald Jr., Helen (sheet D-2)
    - Section 2
    - bar102 1960 1960 Family, House (sheet D-11)
    - Section 3
    - bar103 1961Corvette, Donald Sr. office (sheet D-15)
    - Section 4
    - bar104 1962 Donald Sr. (sheet D-17)
    - bar105 1962 Donald Jr. (sheet D-20)
    - Section 5
    - bar106 1963 Donald Jr. (sheet D-21)
  - (Cd-rom BAR016, File Barthelme Binder 4)
    - bar107 – bar108 1963 Donald Jr. (sheet D-25)
    - bar109 – bar110 1963 Donald Jr. (sheet D-26)
    - bar111 – bar112 1963 Family portrait (sheet D-29)
  - (Cd-rom BAR017, File Barthelme Binder 4)
    - Section 6
    - bar113 1965 Family portrait (sheet D-37)
    - Section 7
    - bar114 1966 Donald Jr. and Birgit (sheet D-51)
    - bar115 1966 Donald Jr. and Birgit (sheet D-52)
    - bar116 1966 1966 Donald Sr. (sheet D-54)
    - Section 8
    - bar117 – bar118 1968 House (sheet D-59)
    - bar119 1968 Donald Sr. (sheet D-60)
    - bar120 1969 Moon landing (sheet D-61)
  - (Cd-rom BAR018, File Barthelme Binder 4)
    - bar121 1969 Donald Sr., Family (sheet D-66)
    - bar122 1969 Donald Jr. apartment, New York City (sheet D-68)
    - Section 9
    - bar123 – bar124 1970 University of Houston architecture studio (sheet D-71)
    - bar125 1970 Family Portrait (sheet D-72)
    - Section 10
    - bar126 1972 Family, Donald Jr. (sheet D-78)
    - bar127 1972 Donald Jr., Daughter (sheet D-79)
    - bar128 1973 Donald Jr., Wife, Daughter (sheet D-85)
    - Section 1 (File Barthelme Binder 5)
    - bar129 1974Donald Jr. (sheet E-4)
  - (Cd-rom BAR019, File Barthelme Binder 5)
    - Section 3
    - bar130 1976 Donald Jr., Daughter, House (sheet E-16)
    - bar131 1976 House (sheet E-17)
    - bar132 1976 House (sheet E-18)
    - bar133 1976 Donald Sr., Family (sheet E-19)
    - bar134 1977 Donald Sr., Helen at new apartment (sheet E-23)
    - Section 4
    - bar135 1978 Donald Jr. apartment, New York City (sheet E-28)
    - bar136 1978 Donald Sr. (sheet E-31)
    - bar137 1978 Lilliotts (sheet E-33)
    - bar138 1980 Donald Jr. (sheet E-36)
  - (Cd-rom BAR020, File Barthelme Binder 5)
    - bar139 1983 Donald Jr., Marion, baby (sheet E-45)
    - bar140 1984 Donald Jr., Marion, baby (sheet E-46)
    - bar141 1984 Donald Sr., Helen, Joan’s family (sheet E-47)
    - bar142 1985 Donald Jr. family, Donald Sr. dancing (sheet E-49)
    - bar143 1985 Donald Jr. on TV (sheet E-51)
    - bar144 - 1951 Donald Jr., Peter, Frederick, Steven (4x5 color)
    - Additional images
    - Section 2 (File Barthelme Binder 1)
    - bar145 1932 Galveston, p. 8
    - Section 3
    - bar146 1943 Barthelme children, new house, 3rd sheet
  - (Cd-rom BAR021, File Barthelme Binder 1)
    - bar147 1943 Barthelme children, new house-color, 3rd sheet
    - Section 4
    - bar148 1948 Barthelme children, 5th sheet
    - bar149 1948 Barthelme children, 6th sheet
    - bar150 1948 Barthelme children, 7th sheet
    - Section 5
    - bar151 1949 Barthelme children, Joan, 11th sheet
    - Section 1 (File Barthelme Binder 3)
    - bar152 1953 Barthelme children, 34th sheet
    - Section 2
    - bar154 1954 Don Sr. with Frederick, Steven, 68th sheet
    - bar155 1954 Don Sr. office, 71st sheet
    - Loose Prints (File Barthelme Binder 5)
    - bar156 ca. 1980 Don and Helen Barthelme-color
    - bar157 ca. 1950's Don Sr. self portrait
  - (Cd-rom BAR022, File Barthelme Binder 5)
    - “Arch”
    - bar158 1951 West Columbia Elementary
    - bar159 1951 West Columbia Elementary
    - bar160 1951 West Columbia Elementary
    - bar161 1960's Rice charette and miscellaneous competitions
    - bar162 1959 Carver School additions and miscellaneous competitions
    - bar163 1959 Highland Heights Elementary
    - bar164 1959 Highland Heights Elementary
    - bar165 1959 Highland Heights and APC 1961 APC Building and tower
    - bar 166 1958 APC Building-color
  - Additional Images (Cd-rom BAR023, File Barthelme Binder 2)
    - Section 1
    - bar167 1950 Helen and Steven (sheet B-7)
    - bar168 1950 Joan (sheet B-16)
    - Section 2
    - bar169 1951 Family at piano (sheet B-60)
    - Section 1 (File Barthelme Binder 3)
    - bar170 1953 Frederick and Steven (28th sheet)
    - Section 2
    - bar171 1954 University of Houston studio, Marilyn and Don, Jr., (52nd sheet)
    - bar172 1954 Don Sr. office, children (57th sheet)
  - Bar001 – Bar172 JPEG images at 300 dpi (Cd-rom BAR024)
  - DVD Backup for BAR001 – BAR007 (Cd-rom BAR025)
  - DVD Backup for BAR008 – BAR014 (Cd-rom BAR026)
  - DVD Backup for BAR015 – BAR020 (Cd-rom BAR027)
  - DVD Backup for BAR021 – BAR023 (Cd-rom BAR028)
  - Binder 1 of 1, containing printouts of raw scans, Bar001 – Bar172 (Box 46)
- Exhibition: Bosquet-Wightman House
  In March 2005, the Houston Mod organization sponsored an exhibition at the Gerald D. Hines College of Architecture concerning Barthelme's Bousquet House (1940). At the time, the house, at 3981 Del Monte Drive in Houston's River Oaks neighborhood, was the last surviving Barthelme-designed residence in the city. It was demolished later in the year. The exhibit coincided with efforts by a class from the University of Houston to document the house for the Historic American Buildings Survey (HABS). The exhibit featured a booklet, detailed photographs and drawings of the house in 2005, a scale model, the HABS drawings, and reproductions of Barthelme's original drawings. Houston Mod donated the exhibition materials to the University of Houston Libraries, Department of Special Collections, where they were added to the Donald Barthelme, Sr. Architectural Papers. The booklet is cataloged separately, but the exhibition boards and model are contained in the following boxes.
  - Exhibit Boards (Box 47)
  - Exhibit Boards (Box 48)
  - Exhibit Boards (Box 49)
  - Model, Bouquet-Wightman House (Box 50)
- Barthelme Personal Library
  Barthelme’s personal library of 59 books was separated from the Donald Barthelme, Sr. Architectural Papers and transferred to the University’s William R. Jenkins Architecture & Art Library, where they were integrated into its Closed Collections and Special Collections. Barthelme earlier donated most of his books to the University’s Architecture Library in 1977 (the name of the library changed in 1986).
  - Aalto, Alvar. Alvar Aalto. Scarsdale, N.Y.: Wittenborn, 1963.
  - Adams, Frank Carter. State of Texas Building, Shrines of Texas Vol. l. Austin: Steck, 1937.
  - Baker, Stephen F. Philosophy of Mathematics. Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1964.
  - Bayer, Herbert, and Walter Gropius and Ise Gropius. Bauhaus 1919-1928. New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1938.
  - Boesiger, W. Le Corbusier et Pierre Jeanneret: Oeuvre Complete de 1910-1929. Zurich: Dr. H. Girsberger, 1937.
  - Boesiger, W. W. Le Corbusier: Oeuvre Complete 1952-1957. Zurich: Girsberger, 1958.
  - Boesiger, W. Le Corbusier: Oeuvre Complete 1946-1952. Zurich: Girsberger, 1955.
  - Boesiger, Willy. Le Corbusier und Pierre Jeanneret ihr Gesamtes Werk von 1929-1934. Zurich: Dr. H. Girsberger, 1935.
  - Boesiger, Willy. Le Corbusier: Oeuvre Complete 1938-1946. Zurich: Les Editions d'Architecture, 1946.
  - Drexler, Arthur. The Architecture of Japan. New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1955.
  - Educational Facilities Laboratories. The Things of Education. New York: Georgian Lithographers, 1961.
  - Educational Facilities Laboratories. New Schools for New Education. New York: Educational Facilities Laboratories, 1959
  - Faber, Tobias. Arne Jacobsen. New York: Praeger, 1964.
  - Fox, Stephen. Houston Architectural Guide. Houston: American Institute of Architects/Houston Chapter and Herring Press, 1990.
  - Fox, Stephen. The General Plan of the William M. Rice Institute and its Architectural Development. Houston: Rice University, 1980.
  - Fuller, Buckminster, Ideas and Integrities: A Spontaneous Autobiographical Disclosure. Englewood Cliff, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1963.
  - Giedion, Sigfried. A Decade of New Architecture. Zurich: Girsberger, 1951.
  - Giedion, Sigfried. Architecture, You and Me: The Diary of a Development. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1958.
  - Goodwin, Philip L. Brazil Builds: Architecture New and Old 1652-1942. New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1943.
  - Hall, Edward T The Hidden Dimension. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1966.
  - Hayakawa, S. I. Language in Action. New York: Harcourt, Brace and Co., 1939.
  - Hitchcock, Henry Russell. Introduction. Philip Johnson Architecture 1949 – 1965. New York: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1966.
  - Hitchcock, Henry-Russell and Arthur Drexler. Built in USA: Post-War Architecture. New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1952(3 copies).
  - Houston Chapter of the American Institute of Architects. 1990 Professional Directory. Houston: American Institute of Architects, 1990.
  - Houston Chapter of the American Institute of Architects. 1992 Professional Directory. Houston: American Institute of Architects, 1992.
  - Jackson, Wes. Man and the Environment. Dubuque, Iowa: Wm. C. Brown, 1971.
  - Jencks, Charles and Nathan Silver. Adhocism: The Case for Improvisation. Garden City, N.Y.: Anchor Book, 1973.
  - Johnson, Philip and Mark Wigley. Deconstructivist Architecture. New York: Museum of Modem Art, 1988.